The Daddy Voice Americans are culturally programmed to trust the deep voices of
authority. In a study from McMaster University in Canada, published in the
Journal of Evolution and Human Behavior, researchers found that men with lower-pitched
voices are found to be more dominant and attractive than are men with
higher-pitched voices. They found that lower-pitched voices are associated with
favorable personality traits more often than our higher-pitched voices. Listeners
were asked to assess the attractiveness, honesty, leadership potential, and
intelligence, among other qualities, of the speakers. For nearly every attribute
they were asked to rate, participants were significantly more likely to prefer the
deeper voice. Think of national broadcasters and the deep, mellifluous
tones they use. If you deepen your voice, you'll find that Americans become more
respectful and attentive. To capture this voice, hark back to when your dad would
call you in for dinner, even if this was never the case. Put your chest out, take a
deep breath and say hey get in here. Notice how that feels physically and
mentally. If you come in through the daddy voice you'll probably have a less negative
reaction than just by deepening your voice randomly to which we've had people say I
sound like a monster, I sound like a gangster. This is not the direction we
want to push you in but rather the calm reassuring voice of an authority figure.
Shoulders back, chin up, chest out, Project from your diaphragm and relax your
throat.